Hi my dear Italian colleague When do you
use HCG on testosterone replacement
Therapy
Thanks Hello Steven it is always an honor
to be your guest and I congratulate you
on your channel from which I
always draw information then the use
of hcg of Gonasi is a drug that
we use in Italy therefore of a
synthetic LH is strongly recommended in
TRT For what reason as we know in
TRT the testosterone that is
aromatized into estrogen causes
the estrogen itself to have an
inhibitory action a so-called negative feedback on the
hypothalamic pituitary axis on the hypothalamic
and pituitary estrogen receptors for which the pituitary gland comes to
produce less FSH and therefore a
significant reduction in spermatogenesis and less LH
which is important for the stimulation on the
cells of the erectile dysfunction. What does this do is that
the testicle certainly loses its
trophism, its volume and therefore a
reduction in the volume of the testicle but
the use of synthetic LH of hcg is not so
much for aesthetic reasons We must
consider that the LH activates an enzyme
cytochrome
p450 which is a kind of scissors is one
of Asi an enzyme that goes to detach the
side chain of cholesterol But what does
all this mean? All
steroid hormones must derive from cholesterol.
Cholesterol through a protein
called star is made to enter the
mitochondrion and in the internal membrane of the
mitochondrion through the cytochrome
p450 the cholesterol is transformed into
premien Olone a
neurostar the Delta 4 and Delta 5 pathways to
become all the steroid hormones that
we know progesterone testosterone
estrogen Dea cortisol if we no
longer have the lh we no longer have
the activator of this enzyme of this
cytochrome
p450 so we go to block the whole
chain let's say assembly of the
steroid hormones for this reason it is
essential in those who are on
hormone replacement therapy to insert
the therapy with hCG weekly.
Let's remember that it has a short half-life so it
is preferable to have an administration
that is at least every two or three days and
at the same time Let's remember that at a
level  intramuscular Most
of the peptides are inactivated by
enzymes, therefore the administration is
always subcutaneous. Here,
let us remember the indispensability
of the use of synthetic hcg during
hormonal treatment with testosterone.
With this, I thank you. I hope to be
your guest again in some other
episode and I greet all your followers.